Guide to the Charles A. Fenton Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Charles A. Fenton papers
1866-1965
1918-1960
YCAL MSS 579
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
21.1
(38 boxes)
The collection consists primarily of material created and accumulated by Charles Fenton in the course of researching and writing books on Stephen Vincent Benét and Ernest Hemingway. Research material includes correspondence about Benét and Hemingway, Fenton's notes about their lives and careers, and index cards with which Fenton organized his research. In addition to research on Benét and Hemingway, the collection contains a smaller amount of research material on the topic of "Writer in America" and the history of The National Institute of Arts and Letters, as well as notes regarding Fenton's World War II anthology and notes on American writers. The collection also contains professional and personal papers, including manuscripts and teaching materials from Fenton's years as a lecturer at Duke University.
Fenton, Charles A., 1919-1960
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Charles A. Fenton, Jr., 1961.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Associated Materials
Charles Andrews Fenton Papers. Manuscripts and Archives, Yale University Library. MS 206.
Charles A. Fenton (1919-1960)
Charles A. Fenton, author and educator, was born in Springfield, Massachusetts in 1919. He is the author of The Apprenticeship of Ernest Hemingway: The Early Years (1954) and Stephen Vincent Benét: The Life and Times of an American Man of Letters (1958). He also edited The Best Short Stories of World War II: An American Anthology (1957) and Selected Letters of Stephen Vincent Benét (1960). He taught English at Yale from 1948 to 1958, and at Duke University from 1958 until his death in 1960.
Scope and Contents
The collection consists primarily of material created and accumulated by Charles Fenton in the course of researching and writing books on Stephen Vincent Benét and Ernest Hemingway. Research material includes correspondence about Benét and Hemingway, Fenton's notes about their lives and careers, and index cards with which Fenton organized his research. In addition to research on Benét and Hemingway, the collection contains a smaller amount of research material on the topic of "Writer in America" and the history of The National Institute of Arts and Letters, as well as notes regarding Fenton's World War II anthology and notes on American writers. The collection also contains professional and personal papers, including manuscripts and teaching materials from Fenton's years as a lecturer at Duke University.
Arrangement
Organized into four series: I. Stephen Vincent Benét Research Material, 1866-1960. II. Ernest Hemingway Research Material, 1929-1959. III. Other Research Material, circa 1955. IV. Personal and Professional Papers, 1946-1965.
American literature -- 20th Century; Authors, American -- 20th Century -- Archives; World War, 1939-1945 -- Literature and the war; Authors -- United States -- 20th Century; Benét, Stephen Vincent, 1898-1943; Fenton, Charles A., 1919-1960; Hemingway, Ernest, 1899-1961
- Stephen Vincent Benét Research Material, 1866-1960; Series I; 12.67; (22 boxes)
  Arrangement
  Organized in three subseries: Correspondence, Notes, and Card Files. Correspondence is arranged alphabetically by correspondent or subject. Notes are arranged roughly alphabetically by topic. The card files are arranged alphabetically by index type.
  Scope and Contents
  Series I. contains Fenton's research materials relating to Stephen Vincent Benét: The Life and Times of an American Man of Letters (1958). The correspondence subseries contains Fenton's correspondence, as well as some copies of letters between Benét and others. The series also contains Fenton's research notes and index card files pertaining to the biography.
  - Correspondence
    - "A" General, 1934-1959, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - "B" General, 1920-1957, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Benét, James W., 1903-1927 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Benét, Laura, 1954-1958 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Benét, Laurence V., 1937-1946 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Benét, Rosemary, 1929-1960, undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Benét, Stephen Vincent, 1866-1957, undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Brandt & Brandt, 1925-1957 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - "C" General, 1919-1960, undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Chicago University, 1928-1955 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - "D" General, 1920-1967 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - "E" General, 1954-1958 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - "F" General, 1954-1958 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Farrar, John, 1955-1958 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Farrell, James T., 1941-1958 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Freeman, Douglas Southall, 1933-1942 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - "G" General, 1938-1957 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Gammell, Susanna, 1954-1958 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - "H" General, 1941-1957 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - "I" General, 1932-1956 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - "J" General, 1937-1957 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - "K" General, 1934-1957 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - "L" General, 1919-1959 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Library of Congress, 1954-1957 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - "M" General, 1925-1957 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - "N" General, 1932-1956 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Nathan, Robert, 1954-1956, undated (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - "O" General, 1955-1958 (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - "P-Q" General, 1936-1958 (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - "R" General, 1928-1958 (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - Rinehart & Company, 1941-1955 (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - Rochester, University of, 1940-1956 (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - "S" General, 1928-1957, undated (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - "T" General, 1929-1957 (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - "U" General, 1955-1956 (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - "V" General, 1954-1958 (Box 2, Folder 36)
    - "W" General, 1928-1958 (Box 2, Folder 37)
    - "X-Z" General, 1919-1957 (Box 2, Folder 38)
    - Unidentified, 1923-1955, undated (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Notes, circa 1955
    - Abbe, George (Box 3, Folder 40)
    - Abroad (reception, influence, publications, etc.) (Box 3, Folder 41)
    - Adams, F. P. (Box 3, Folder 42)
    - All That Money Can Buy (1941) (Box 3, Folder 43)
    - Academic (Box 3, Folder 44)
    - Academy of Arts and Letters (Box 3, Folder 45)
    - America (1944) (Box 3, Folder 46-47)
    - American Magazine (Box 3, Folder 48)
    - Anderson, Maxwell (Box 3, Folder 49)
    - Andrews, Charles M. (Box 3, Folder 50)
    - Andrews, John (Box 3, Folder 51)
    - Another Little Boy - play (1924) (Box 3, Folder 52)
    - Art (Box 3, Folder 53)
    - Atchley, Dana W. (Box 3, Folder 54)
    - Atlantic Monthly (Box 3, Folder 55)
    - Auslander, V. (Box 3, Folder 56)
    - Bacon, Leonard (Box 3, Folder 57)
    - Badger, Shreve (Box 3, Folder 58)
    - The Ballad of the Duke's Mercy (1939) (Box 3, Folder 59)
    - Ballad of Marco Polo (1937) (Box 3, Folder 60)
    - Ballad of William Sycamore (1923) (Box 3, Folder 61)
    - Ballads and Poems 1915-1930 (1931) (Box 3, Folder 62)
    - The Barefoot Saint (1929) (Box 3, Folder 63)
    - Barney, Danforth (Box 3, Folder 64)
    - Barry, Phillip (Box 3, Folder 65)
    - Beebe, Lucius (Box 3, Folder 66)
    - Beeson, Charles H. (Box 3, Folder 67)
    - The Beginning of Wisdom (1921) (Box 3, Folder 68)
    - Bellinger, Alfred (Box 3, Folder 69)
    - Benét Children: Stephanie Jane, b. April 6, 1924; Thomas Carr, b. Sept. 28, 1926 (Box 3, Folder 70)
    - Benét Frances Neill (mother of SVB) (Box 3, Folder 71)
    - Benét Grandparents, etc. (Box 3, Folder 72)
    - Benét, Col. James Walker (father of SVB) (Box 3, Folder 73)
    - Benét, James W., II (nephew of SVB) (Box 3, Folder 74)
    - Benét, Laura (sister of SVB) (Box 3, Folder 75)
    - Benét, Mrs. J. W. (Box 3, Folder 76)
    - Benét, Laurence (uncle of SVB) (Box 3, Folder 77)
    - Benét, Rachel (daughter of SVB) (Box 3, Folder 78)
    - Benét, Rosemary (Mrs. Stephen Vincent Benét) (Box 3, Folder 79)
    - Benét, Stephen Vincent
      - Childhood, 1898-1905 (Box 4, Folder 80)
      - Childhood, 1906-1911 (Box 4, Folder 81)
      - Childhood, 1911-1915 (Box 4, Folder 82)
      - Benét, 1915-1919 (Box 4, Folder 83)
      - Benét at Yale (Box 4, Folder 84)
      - Benét at Yale: Yale Literary Magazine (Box 4, Folder 85)
      - Benét at Yale: Yale Record (Box 4, Folder 86)
      - Benét at Yale: Academic (Box 4, Folder 87)
      - Benét at Yale: Reminiscence about (Box 4, Folder 88)
      - Benét at Yale: Use of Yale in mature work (Box 4, Folder 89)
      - Benét at Yale: Wolf's Head (Box 4, Folder 90)
      - SVB at Yale: Larry Mason (Box 4, Folder 91)
      - SVB at Yale: The Literary Renaissance (Box 4, Folder 92)
      - Graduate School, 1919-1920 (Box 4, Folder 93)
      - Benét, 1920-1924 (Box 4, Folder 94-98)
      - Benét, 1925-1929 (Box 5, Folder 99-103)
      - Depression Years (Box 5, Folder 104)
      - Benét, 1930-1935 (Box 5, Folder 105-110)
      - Benét, 1936-1949 (Box 6, Folder 111-119)
      - Manuscripts (SV Benét) (Box 7, Folder 120)
      - Correspondence: diary entries (Box 7, Folder 121)
      - SVB - Misc. (chapter heads, etc.) (Box 7, Folder 122)
      - Miscellaneous - anthologies, etc. (Box 7, Folder 123)
      - As Reviewer (Box 7, Folder 124)
      - Reviews by SVB, 1921-1938 (Box 7, Folder 125-126)
      - Reviews by SVB, 1939-1943 (Box 7, Folder 127-129)
    - Benét, Thomas Carr (son of SVB) (Box 8, Folder 130)
    - Benét, William Rose (Box 8, Folder 131)
    - Berdan (Box 8, Folder 132)
    - A Book of Americans (with Rosemary Benét) (1933) (Box 8, Folder 133)
    - Bookman (Box 8, Folder 134)
    - Brandt & Brandt (Box 8, Folder 135)
    - Brewer, Leighton (Box 8, Folder 136)
    - Bronson, F. W. (Box 8, Folder 137)
    - Brooks, Van Wyck (Box 8, Folder 138)
    - Burning City (1936) (Box 8, Folder 139)
    - Cabell, James Branch (Box 8, Folder 140)
    - Campbell, Donald Malcolm (Box 8, Folder 141)
    - Canby, H. S. (Box 8, Folder 142)
    - Carmer, Carl (Box 8, Folder 143)
    - Carter, Henry (Box 8, Folder 144)
    - Carter, John Franklin, Jr. (Box 8, Folder 145)
    - Century Club (Box 8, Folder 146)
    - Century Magazine (Box 8, Folder 147)
    - Chase, Rodney (Box 8, Folder 148)
    - Child, Charles (Box 8, Folder 149)
    - Chubb, T. C. (Box 8, Folder 150)
    - Coale, Griffith B. (Box 8, Folder 151)
    - Collier's (Box 8, Folder 152)
    - Cosmopolitan (Box 8, Folder 153)
    - Council for Democracy (Box 8, Folder 154)
    - Country Gentleman Fiction (1927) (Box 8, Folder 155)
    - Critics (Box 8, Folder 156)
    - Damrosch (Box 9, Folder 157)
    - Darroch, Lois (Box 9, Folder 158)
    - Davenport, Russell (Box 9, Folder 159)
    - Decision (Box 9, Folder 160)
    - De Jong, David C. (Box 9, Folder 161)
    - Delineator (1922) (Box 9, Folder 162)
    - The Devil and Daniel Webster (1937) (Box 9, Folder 163)
    - The Devil and Daniel Webster (opera) with Douglas Moore (1939) (Box 9, Folder 164)
    - Dieterle, William (Box 9, Folder 165)
    - Dos Passos, John (Box 9, Folder 166)
    - Douglas, William (1918) (Box 9, Folder 167)
    - The Drug-Shop (1917) (Box 9, Folder 168)
    - Eliot (Box 9, Folder 169)
    - Elk's Magazine (Box 9, Folder 170)
    - Engle, Paul (Box 9, Folder 171)
    - Everybody's (Box 9, Folder 172)
    - Family Relations (Box 9, Folder 173-174)
    - Farrar, John (Box 9, Folder 175)
    - Farrar & Rinehart (Box 9, Folder 176)
    - Farrell, James T. (Box 9, Folder 177)
    - Faulkner, William (Box 9, Folder 178)
    - Finances (Box 9, Folder 179)
    - Finkelstein, Louis (Box 9, Folder 180)
    - Fitzgerald, F. Scott (Box 9, Folder 181)
    - Five Men and Pompey (1915) (Box 9, Folder 182)
    - Fortune (Box 9, Folder 183)
    - The Free Company (Box 9, Folder 184)
    - Freeman, Douglas S. (Box 9, Folder 185)
    - Frost (Box 9, Folder 186)
    - Gammell, Mrs. Mitchell (Box 9, Folder 187)
    - University of Georgia poem (Box 9, Folder 188)
    - Golden Book (Box 9, Folder 189)
    - Good Housekeeping (Box 9, Folder 190)
    - Hagedorn, Hermann (Box 10, Folder 191)
    - Hale, Nancy (Box 10, Folder 192)
    - Harper's (Box 10, Folder 193)
    - Harper's Bazaar (Box 10, Folder 194)
    - Hazard, Thomas P. & Nancy (Box 10, Folder 195)
    - The Headless Horseman (1937) (Box 10, Folder 196)
    - Health (Box 10, Folder 197)
    - Heavens & Earth (Box 10, Folder 198)
    - "The Hemp" (1916 January) (Box 10, Folder 199)
    - [Hendricks,] Grace (Box 10, Folder 200)
    - Henriques, Robert (Box 10, Folder 201)
    - Hitchcock Military Academy (Box 10, Folder 202)
    - Hollywood (Box 10, Folder 203)
    - Hopwood (Box 10, Folder 204)
    - Howard, Sidney (Box 10, Folder 205)
    - The Island and the Fire (1930) (Box 10, Folder 206)
    - James Shore's Daughter (1934) (Box 10, Folder 207)
    - "Jean Huguenot" (1923) (Box 10, Folder 208)
    - John Brown's Body, research (Box 10, Folder 209)
    - John Brown's Body (1927-1928) (Box 10, Folder 210-211)
    - John Brown's Body, Laughton Adaptation (1952) (Box 10, Folder 212)
    - John Brown's Body (1928) (Box 11, Folder 213)
    - John Brown's Body (American Library) (Box 11, Folder 214-215)
    - John Brown's Body, reviews (Box 11, Folder 216)
    - John Brown's Body, reception (Box 11, Folder 217)
    - Johnny Pye and the Fool Killer (1938) (Box 11, Folder 218)
    - King David (1923) (Box 11, Folder 219)
    - The King of the Cats (1929) (Box 11, Folder 220)
    - Ladies' Home Journal (Box 11, Folder 221)
    - LaFarge, Christopher (Box 11, Folder 222)
    - The Last Circle (1946) (Box 11, Folder 223)
    - Lectures (Box 11, Folder 224)
    - Lewis, W. "Duffy" Sergant (Box 11, Folder 225)
    - Liberty (Box 11, Folder 226)
    - Listen to the People (1941) (Box 11, Folder 227)
    - Literary criticism (Box 11, Folder 228)
    - Literary life (Box 11, Folder 229)
    - Locke, Florence (Box 11, Folder 230)
    - Longwell, Daniel (Box 11, Folder 231)
    - Loveman, Amy (Box 11, Folder 232)
    - Luke, Henry (Box 11, Folder 233)
    - McClure, Robert E. (Box 11, Folder 234)
    - McCall's (Box 11, Folder 235)
    - MacLeish, Archibald (Box 11, Folder 236)
    - McNeill, Louise (Box 11, Folder 237)
    - Magic of Poetry (1936) (Box 12, Folder 238)
    - Marquand (Box 12, Folder 239)
    - Masefield, J. (Box 12, Folder 240)
    - Massey (Box 12, Folder 241)
    - Masters (Box 12, Folder 242)
    - Millay, Edna St. Vincent (Box 12, Folder 243)
    - Millis, Walter (Box 12, Folder 244)
    - Monroe, Harriet (Box 12, Folder 245)
    - Mountain Whipperwill (1925) (Box 12, Folder 246)
    - Moore, Douglas (Box 12, Folder 247)
    - Meyers, Richard (Box 12, Folder 248)
    - Nathan, Robert (Box 12, Folder 249)
    - Nerves, play (September 1924) (Box 12, Folder 250)
    - New Republic (Box 12, Folder 251)
    - New York (Box 12, Folder 252-253)
    - New Yorker (poetry) (Box 12, Folder 254)
    - Nightmare at Noon (1940) (Box 12, Folder 255)
    - Ode to Walt Whitman (1935) (Box 12, Folder 256)
    - Parabalou (1920-1921) (Box 12, Folder 257)
    - Other writers (Box 12, Folder 258)
    - Peacedale, Rhode Island (Box 12, Folder 259)
    - Perry, Lewis (Box 12, Folder 260)
    - Personal characteristics (Box 13, Folder 261-263)
    - Photos (Box 13, Folder 264)
    - Pictorial Review (Box 13, Folder 265)
    - Politics (Box 13, Folder 266)
    - Politics, 1932-1938 (Box 13, Folder 267-273)
    - Power and the Land [REA] (1940) (Box 13, Folder 274)
    - Prayer: A Child is Born (1944) (Box 13, Folder 275)
    - Radio (Box 14, Folder 276)
    - Reader's Digest (Box 14, Folder 277)
    - Redbook fiction (1922-) (Box 14, Folder 278)
    - Reputation, influence, public responses, etc. (Box 14, Folder 279)
    - Rinehart, Stanley & F. (Box 14, Folder 280)
    - Rip Van Winkle (1936) (Box 14, Folder 281)
    - Rivers of America [co-editor] (Box 14, Folder 282)
    - Robinson, E. A. (Box 14, Folder 283)
    - Rodman, Selden (Box 14, Folder 284)
    - Roosevelt, Franklin D. (Box 14, Folder 285)
    - Roosevelt, Theodore (Box 14, Folder 286)
    - Rosten, Norman (Box 14, Folder 287)
    - Rukeyser, Muriel (Box 14, Folder 288)
    - S4N (1919-) (Box 14, Folder 289)
    - St. Nicholas (Box 14, Folder 290)
    - Sandburg, Carl (Box 14, Folder 291)
    - Saturday Evening Post (Box 14, Folder 292)
    - Saturday Review of Literature (Box 14, Folder 293)
    - Scholastic (Box 14, Folder 294)
    - Selected Works of Stephen Vincent Benét (1942) (Box 14, Folder 295)
    - Shepardson, Whitney (Box 14, Folder 296)
    - "Six of us Talking" in Zero Hour (N.Y., 1940) (Box 14, Folder 297)
    - "The Sixth Man" (1957) (Box 14, Folder 298)
    - Smith, Chard Powers (Box 14, Folder 299)
    - Social life (Box 14, Folder 300)
    - Spanish Bayonet (1926) (Box 14, Folder 301)
    - Stevenson, Burton E. (Box 14, Folder 302)
    - Stonington (Box 14, Folder 303)
    - Tales Before Midnight (1939) (Box 14, Folder 304)
    - Taylor, Deems (Box 14, Folder 305)
    - That Awful Mrs. Eaton (September 29, 1924) (Box 14, Folder 306)
    - Theater (Box 14, Folder 307)
    - They Burned Books (1942) (Box 14, Folder 308)
    - Thirteen O'Clock (1937) (Box 14, Folder 309)
    - Thurber, James (Box 14, Folder 310)
    - Tiger Joy (1925) (Box 14, Folder 311)
    - Town & Country (Box 14, Folder 312)
    - United Nations (Box 14, Folder 313)
    - Valentine, Alan (Box 14, Folder 314)
    - Van Gelder, Robert (Box 14, Folder 315)
    - War Propaganda (Box 14, Folder 316)
    - West Point (Box 14, Folder 317)
    - Whitman, Walt (Box 14, Folder 318)
    - Westand United, 1945 (Box 15, Folder 319)
    - Western Star (1945) (Box 15, Folder 320)
    - Widdemer, Margaret (Box 15, Folder 321)
    - Wilder, Thornton (Box 15, Folder 322)
    - Wilkie, Wendel (Box 15, Folder 323)
    - Winslow, Ann (Box 15, Folder 324)
    - Winterich, John T. (Box 15, Folder 325)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 15, Folder 326)
    - Woman's Day (Box 15, Folder 327)
    - Wooley, Monty (Box 15, Folder 328)
    - World War I (Box 15, Folder 329)
    - World War II (Box 15, Folder 330)
    - Writer's War Board (Box 15, Folder 331)
    - Writing - attitude towards (Box 15, Folder 332)
    - Writing - editors (Box 15, Folder 333)
    - Writing (Box 15, Folder 334)
    - Writing - method (Box 16, Folder 335)
    - Writing - poetry (Box 16, Folder 336)
    - Writing - satire (Box 16, Folder 337)
    - Writing - short stories (Box 16, Folder 338)
    - Wylie, E. (Box 16, Folder 339)
    - The Yale Book of Student Verse, ed. John W. Andrews, SVB, John Chipman Farrar & Pierson Underwood (Yale University Press, 1919) (Box 16, Folder 340)
    - Yale Review (Box 16, Folder 341)
    - Yale Series of Younger Poets (Box 16, Folder 342)
    - Yeats, William Butler (Box 16, Folder 343)
    - Young Adventure (1918) (Box 16, Folder 344)
    - Young People's Pride (1922) (Box 16, Folder 345)
    - Young writers (Box 16, Folder 346)
    - "You've Got to Be Rich" [with C. LaFarge & R. Myers] (1938) (Box 16, Folder 347)
  - Card Files, circa 1955
    - Bibliography (Box 17)
    - Citations, filed alphabetically (Box 18)
    - Citations, filed chronologically (Box 19)
    - Correspondence - general, filed alphabetically (Box 20)
    - Correspondence - family (Box 21)
    - Sources, filed alphabetically (Box 22)
- Ernest Hemingway Research Material, 1929-1959; Series II; 5.09; (8 boxes)
  Organized into three subseries: Correspondence, Notes, and Card Files. Correspondence is arranged alphabetically by correspondent, followed by copies of Hemingway correspondence. Notes are arranged roughly alphabetically by topic. Card files are arranged alphabetically by index type.
  Series II. contains Fenton's correspondence regarding his biography about Ernest Hemingway, as well as copies of Hemingway's correspondence with Fenton, Guy Hickok, and others. It also contains Fenton's research notes and card files for the biography.
  - Correspondence, 1929-1959
    - "A" General, 1952-1954 (Box 23, Folder 348)
    - "B" General, 1952-1954 (Box 23, Folder 349)
    - "C" General, 1951-1954 (Box 23, Folder 350)
    - "D" General, 1952 (Box 23, Folder 351)
    - "E-F" General, 1951-1955 (Box 23, Folder 352)
    - "G" General, 1950-1953 (Box 23, Folder 353)
    - "H" General, 1951-1955 (Box 23, Folder 354)
    - "I-K" General, 1951-1953 (Box 23, Folder 355)
    - "L" General, 1952-1959 (Box 23, Folder 356)
    - "M" General, 1951-1957 (Box 23, Folder 357)
    - "N-O" General, 1952-1953 (Box 23, Folder 358)
    - "P" General, 1952-1953 (Box 23, Folder 359)
    - "R" General, 1952-1953 (Box 24, Folder 360)
    - "S" General, 1950-1952 (Box 24, Folder 361)
    - "T-V" General, 1951-1953 (Box 24, Folder 362)
    - "Wa-Wi" General, 1951-1952 (Box 24, Folder 363)
    - "Wo-Z" General, 1952-1953 (Box 24, Folder 364)
    - Unidentified, 1951, undated (Box 24, Folder 365)
    - Hemingway, Ernest to others, "A-Z" (copies), 1918-1953 (Box 24, Folder 366)
    - Hemingway, Ernest to Guy Hickok (copies), 1928-1931, undated (Box 24, Folder 367)
    - Hickok, Guy to Ernest Hemingway (copies), 1929-1932 (Box 24, Folder 368)
    - Hemingway, Ernest to Fenton (copies), 1951-1954 (Box 24, Folder 369)
  - Notes, circa 1955
    - Hemingway [Ambulance Service], 1918-1919 (Box 25, Folder 370)
    - Hemingway [in Ambulence Corps], 1918-1919, Reminiscence (Box 25, Folder 371)
    - Hemingway [in World War I], 1918-1919, Arditi (Box 25, Folder 372)
    - Across the River (1950) (Box 25, Folder 373)
    - Anderson, Sherwood (Box 25, Folder 374)
    - Hemingway [Co-operative Society of America], Chicago, 1920 (Box 25, Folder 375)
    - Hemingway in Chicago (Box 25, Folder 376)
    - Hemingway in Chicago, [Co-operative Commonwealth], Hemingway and Anderson (Box 25, Folder 377-378)
    - Death in the Afternoon (1932) (Box 25, Folder 379)
    - Esquire (Box 25, Folder 380)
    - A Farewell to Arms (1929) (Box 25, Folder 381)
    - A Farewell to Arms (drama) (Box 25, Folder 382)
    - The Fifth Column (Box 25, Folder 383)
    - For Whom the Bell Tolls (Box 25, Folder 384)
    - Green Hills of Africa (Box 25, Folder 385)
    - Hemingway, 1927-1940 (Box 25, Folder 386-400)
    - Hemingway, 1941-1954 (Box 26, Folder 401-414)
    - Hemingway in Kansas City
      - Theodore B. Brumback (Box 26, Folder 415)
      - J. Charles Edgar (Box 26, Folder 416)
      - John Patrick Gilday (Box 26, Folder 417)
      - Henry J. Haskell (Box 26, Folder 418)
      - Charles Hopkins (Box 26, Folder 419)
      - Star stories by Hemingway (Box 26, Folder 420)
      - Hemingway on Star, Kansas City (Box 26, Folder 421)
      - Lionel Moise (Box 26, Folder 422)
      - Reminiscence about him on Star (Box 26, Folder 423)
      - City Room interest in writing (Box 26, Folder 424)
      - The Star as a training school (Box 26, Folder 425)
      - Style book (Box 26, Folder 426)
      - Pete Wellington (Box 26, Folder 427)
    - Hemingway and KEN, 1938 (Box 26, Folder 428)
    - In Our Time (1925) (Box 26, Folder 429)
    - Letters (Box 26, Folder 430)
    - Manuscripts (Box 26, Folder 431)
    - Max Eastman (Box 26, Folder 432)
    - Men Without Women (October 14, 1927) (Box 26, Folder 433)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 26, Folder 434-435)
    - NANA Dispatches from Spain, 1937 (Box 27, Folder 436)
    - Parodies (Box 27, Folder 437)
    - The Old Man and the Sea (1952) (Box 27, Folder 438)
    - PM, 1941 (Box 27, Folder 439)
    - The Sun Also Rises (1926) (Box 27, Folder 440)
    - Three Stories and Ten Poems (Box 27, Folder 441)
    - Hemingway in Toronto
      - Hemingway in Toronto (Box 27, Folder 442-443)
      - Lausanne Conference & William Bolitho (Box 27, Folder 444)
      - INS, Universal, 1922-1924 (Box 27, Folder 445-446)
      - Lloyd George in Canada, 1923 (Box 27, Folder 447)
      - Joseph Alkinson (Box 27, Folder 448)
      - John Bone (Box 27, Folder 449)
      - Callaghan (Box 27, Folder 450)
      - Canada - Ontario - Toronto, Journalism (Box 27, Folder 451)
      - Greg Clark (Box 27, Folder 452)